## Joe Peel - Curriculum Vitae

Address: Wolverton, Milton Keynes Tel: 07507 948 566 Email: joe.peel@live.com DOB: 10.01.91

### **Profile**

I've been working in recruitment for the past several years. I'm now looking to switch careers and become a professional web developer. I've been using online resources such as Udemy, Treehouse, Stack Overflow and w3schools to get a grasp of several web technologies.

You can see my portfolio here - www.joepeel.co.uk.

So far, I've worked with:

- HTML and CSS (plus SASS)
- Bootstrap 4
- JavaScript (parts of ES6, learning more!), jQuery, AJAX and Vue.js (inc Vuex and Vue Router)
- PHP and MySQL
- Firebase Realtime Database

Over the next few weeks I'm going to create a Github account, see what I can push / contribute and continue with my online courses.

### **Career History**

**Talent Acquisition Specialist** (Contract) at SMC Pneumatics UK Aug 2016 – Present

In this role I am responsible for the vast majority of the company's recruitment covering engineering, production, sales, finance, customer service and facilities. This involves:

- Qualifying new roles with managers and acquiring sign off
- Interviewing candidates and setting up psychometric assessments (McQuaig)
- Advertising vacancies on LinkedIn and proactively searching for candidates
- Conducting 3 and 6 month reviews
- Managing agencies and negotiating terms of business
- Preparing contracts and training / induction plans

I have also implemented new processes and systems to better track / organise candidates, vacancies, managers and agencies. This in the long term has saved time and allowed for important data to be accessed quickly and easily.

# Recruitment Consultant at Pytec IT Recruitment

Feb 2014 – Jul 2016

At Pytec I built up a desk consisting of clients varying in size both locally and further afield. I've placed candidates across a wide range of positions covering:

- IT Developers, Business Analysts, Project Managers, Network Engineers, 1st/2nd/3rd line support
- Marketing Executives, Managers, Designers, Copywriters Digital SEO, PPC, Social Media and Email Marketing Executives
- Customer service and sales Account Managers, Multilingual Customer Service Executives, Order Processors

Membership Sales Advisor at Everyone ActiveSep 2013 - Feb 2014Negotiator at ConnellsJan 2012 - Aug 2013Travelling AustraliaJune 2011 - September 2011Call Handler at NHS Direct (Conduit)May 2010 - May 2011Travelling ThailandJan 2010 - March 2010Gym Instructor at Serco - Swan Pool Leisure CentreMarch 2008 - Dec 2009

#### **Education**

Buckingham Secondary School - 5 GCSEs including maths, English and science (Finished 2007)

Premier Global - Level 3 Diploma in Personal Training, Level 2 Gym Instructor

### **Interests**

I enjoy playing golf, pool, going to the gym and on holiday.